Okay, at this point,
we really spent a lot of time on components and props,
it's time to move on.
And which other React concept is extremely important,
and is getting used in pretty much all React apps?
State.
Because whilst components
are those reusable building blocks,
state is what makes a React application
truly dynamic and interactive,
because state is the thing that, in the end,
leads to different UIs being rendered,
for example, in response to button clicks.
And speaking of that, here I will add a button,
and we'll later add a complete form,
but for the moment, it's just a button,
where I'll say Add Goal.
And, of course, the goal now is to add a new goal
whenever this button is clicked.
At the moment, with some predefined dummy data,
later, with custom data.
So, in order to make this happen,
I'll start by adding a nested function in the App function,
which I'll name handleAddGoal.
The name is up to you, but this is a common convention
for naming your event handler functions,
so, functions that should be triggered upon some event.
An alternative would be addGoalHandler,
you also see that a lot.
And in the end, the name is up to you,
it just should describe what the function does.
And here, the goal is to dynamically add more and more goals
to this app.
So, therefore, I'll add the onClick prop to this button,
the built-In onClick prop,
and point at handleAddGoal here,
so that this function is triggered
whenever this button here is pressed.
And in here, I now want to generate new goals,
and then dynamically output them on the screen.
And for that, as mentioned, we'll need state.
And we can register some state here in this App component,
of course, with help of the built-in useState hook,
which must be imported from React,
and which is now not just some type,
but instead a real function that we can execute.
Now, as you know,
useState returns an array with exactly two elements,
and the first element is the current state snapshot
for this current function execution cycle,
the second element is a function we can call
to update that state snapshot,
and to trigger this component function
to be executed again, therefore,
because that's how React works.
So, here, I wanna manage some goals,
and therefore my initial state could be an empty array.
And then here, in handleAddGoal,
we can add the logic for manipulating this array
with help of setGoals.
But before we do that,
there's one important problem we should solve,
or one improvement we should make here.
If we hover over goals, we see the type of that,
and at the moment, it's never array,
an array of nevers, which sounds pretty weird.
What does this mean?
In the end, that TypeScript's way of expressing
that this here is an array of unknown types,
and therefore we'll actually also never be able
to tweak this,
because if I, for example,
try to set goals to an array of numbers, I get an error,
because I haven't defined which types of values
should be allowed in this array
when I initialized the state.
So, the general problem which we have to solve here
simply is, that when using React with TypeScript,
and when using useState in such projects,
we have to tell React which type of value
we're going to manage with useState.
Sometimes, it's able to infer this.
If we would set this to some initial text, for example,
it would then infer that goals is of type string.
But for more complex types, like arrays,
which is, as you learned in the end,
a connection of multiple types,
the array, and then the type of value in the array,
in such cases, TypeScript, of course,
is not able to infer anything.
That's why useState is a generic function,
and allows us to add these angle brackets
to pass this extra type information
between those angle brackets.
So, in case of useState,
we can use these angle brackets to set the type of value
that will eventually be managed by that state.
And here, we can make it clear
that this should be an array of course goals,
which, in the end,
should be objects with a title and a description,
and maybe also an ID,
which we'll need later for deleting them.
That's why I will add a new type here, CourseGoal,
which will have a title of type string,
and a description of type string,
and then also, let's say, an ID of type number, maybe.
And with that type defined here,
between those angle brackets,
we can say that the state we want to manage here
should be an array of CourseGoals.
And, as you learned,
that's the syntax for defining
that you want to have an array of a certain value.
The alternative would be to use
the built-in generic Array type.
One of the two must be used here,
and with that, setting our goals to an array of numbers,
of course, will fail,
but now goals, on the other hand,
is inferred to be of the correct type,
and that now allows us to update the type accordingly,
as long as we do it in a correct way.
So, as long as we make sure that goals ends up
being such an array of CourseGoals.
And that's therefore now how we should write the code
in this handleAddGoal function.