[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] So we're able
to fetch our posts here.
But of course, in reality
this is not always going to be super fast.
We might need to wait for our backend
for a couple of milliseconds or seconds
and therefore we might want to show
some loading fallback text
whilst we're waiting for a response.
And of course things can also go wrong.
And I want to @handle@ these two scenarios as well, therefore.
Now let's start with the loading @state@.
To @handle@ that,
we can add a new @state@ to that @component@,
a new @state@ with help of the useState @hook@ of course,
which is our isFetching @state@,
which we update with setIsFetching.
And initially that should be @false@,
but of course here inside of fetchPosts
in that @effect@ @function@,
right at the start, we wanna call setIsFetching
and set that to @true@
because we're sending that request here.
Of course, we then also wanna setIsFetching
back to @false@ once we're done here at the end.
And then with setIsFetching being called
and being set to @true@ or @false@,
we can go to the @component@ @function@
and change the @value@ of content if we're currently fetching.
So we can check if isFetching is @true@,
and in that case set content equal to a paragraph
with an @id@ of loading dash fallback
because I prepared some styles for that @id@.
And here we could then say fetchingPosts dot, dot dot.
And we can see this in @action@ if we go back to our page
and open the developer tools.
And then there, if you go to the network tab,
because there in Chrome you can throttle the network
and simulate a slower network.
For example, by simulating slow 3G.
If you do that and you then reload,
it will take some time to fetch that @data@
because during development all these code files
are extremely big and not optimized.
But then you'll see that fetching post text at least briefly
and with that, I'll disable throttling.
But this loading text therefore is shown as intended.
Now to conclude this example,
I also want to implement error handling
so that if sending this request fails,
the app doesn't simply break,
but we instead shows error message to the user.
Now since we're using this utility @function@,
which will throw an error if we get back an error response,
all we have to do is wrap this get call here
into a try catch block,
like this where we catch an error.
Of course the code that depends
on the success of this fetch request
also should go into the tri block now though.
So here where we update the fetched posts
that should also go in there.
This code here where we set isFetching back to @false@,
should however, stay outside of the try-catch block
because no matter if we got an error or not,
we're not fetching anymore.
Therefore this should definitely be set to @false@ again.
And it's now here in the catch block
where the error should be handled.
For this we can add a third @state@, an error @state@,
which I'll name error and setError @state@ updating @function@.
And this should eventually be a @string@, or @undefined@,
which is the initial @value@.
And then here in the catch block,
we can set this error @state@ by calling set error
and we can set it to a message like failed to fetch posts
like this.
We could also use the message
of the error that's being thrown.
So for example of this error
where the message would be failed to fetch @data@.
Now for that we have to access this error @object@
that's being caught here
and use that in our set error @state@ updating call.
And for example, set this to error.message.
The problem with that just is that error by default
is of @type@ unknown
because @TypeScript@ doesn't know what it's catching here.
In JavaScript, you can throw anything as an error
including @numbers@, strings, anything.
So @TypeScript@ doesn't know
what @type@ of @value@ it will get here
and therefore we either have to add some checks here
and check if error, for example has a certain @property@
or if the @type@ of error, for example
is @string@ or something like this.
We can do all of that,
but for this application here,
we know that it will be an error @object@.
Therefore we can also just use @type@ casting here
and tell @TypeScript@ that this will be of @type@ error.
Alternatively, and a bit cleaner,
we could add an if check and check if error
is an instance of the error class.
This is another operator that's built into JavaScript
and that can be used to get through
if error is based on this error class,
which is built into JavaScript or @false@ if it's not.
And that would then also allow us
to access the message @property@ in a safe way.
And that's arguably the cleaner way.
So I'll use this approach here.
With that, we can then use this error @state@
to show an error message on the screen if we have an error.
So therefore we can, for example here check
if error is truthy, because keep in mind
that initially error is @undefined@, which would be falsey.
So if it's a @string@ if it has some content,
it will be truthy.
And if that's the case, content should be set equal
to that special error message @component@,
which I already prepared for you,
which wants a text @prop@.
So here we can set content equal to ErrorMessage.
For that of course you must @import@ this @component@.
And then here we can set the text @prop@ to error like this.
And with that we should also be handling errors.
So if we now deliberately break the app
by sending the request to an endpoint that doesn't exist
and we then save this.
If I reload here, I get this error box.
So that works as intended.
And of course if we go back
to the valid API endpoint again slash posts
and we then save this and reload
we got those posts again and the error is gone.
And there also is no error here in the console.