So to update this @state@ here
in handleAddGoal,
I'll use this @function@ form for updating my @state@
because the @state@ will be updated
based on the previous @state@ snapshot.
And as you also learn
in my "React - The Complete Guide" course,
if your new @state@ depends on the old @state@,
you should use this special @function@ form
for updating the @state@.
Because here you'll automatically
get your previous @state@ snapshot at the point of time
where this @state@ updating @function@ here
is executed by @React@.
And then here in this @function@ body,
you must return the updated array, in this case,
the updated array of goals.
Well, and here where I want to add a new goal,
that in the end just means
that I want to spread my existing goals array
into this new array.
So I wanna copy all the elements of the existing array
into this new array,
and then add a new object,
a new object of that shape
to be precise to the end or beginning of that array.
So here, all created in a separate step
to keep that code readable,
and add a new goal constant here,
which should be of type CourseGoal.
And I'm adding this explicit type assignment here
to force me to set up a correct value here
and to get better autocompletion
where the IDE now suggests these property names.
So that's another use case
for using explicit type assignments to get this extra safety
so that I don't accidentally set up the wrong type
and to get that extra IDE support.
And then here I can set the id,
let's say to Math.random,
which is good enough for this demo project,
set the title to Learn @React@ + TypeScript in this case,
for the moment, it will be hard-coded,
and set description to Learn it in depth,
which of course means that at the moment
we'll always add the same goal,
but that will of course change soon.
And with that, it's now this new goal,
which is added here in my case,
at the end of this returned new @state@ snapshot,
so that new goals array
that were in the end setting up here.
And with that, we can now finally use goals
to dynamically output this list of CourseGoal components.
And that of course works just as you know it.
We can use this goals @state@, and then the map method
to convert this list of CourseGoal objects
to a list of CourseGoal components,
for example.
And for that we pass a @function@ to map
where we get our individual goal
and where we then return the element
we want to output for every goal.
And here I actually want to output a list item,
and then in that list item, my CourseGoal component.
Because I will actually wrap that entire list
with the unordered list element
so that we got a semantically correct piece of code here.
Now what's really great about TypeScript
is how well it's able to understand your code
and infer types in different places of your code.
For example, TypeScript understands how map works
and it understands that this goal,
which we get as a parameter in this @function@ here,
will be of type CourseGoal
because TypeScript understands
that this @function@ here will be executed for us
by the browser in the end.
And that this value will automatically be populated
and that we will get the values of this array here.
And since this array contains a bunch of course goals,
TypeScript understands that an individual item of that array
will be of type CourseGoal.
And that gives us extra type safety
and great autocompletion here.
For example, when setting the title,
I can now type goal.,
and my IDE understands
that I can now either access the title,
description, or id property
because these are the three properties
I set up in my object type here.
And with that, we can output the title here,
and then output goal.description here
between the paragraph tags.
And then on the list item,
also add the special key @prop@
which @React@ once when outputting such a list,
which should be said equal to goal.id here.
And with that,
finally, we can save that all.
And if we go back here,
we got this button
which we can press to output a bunch of course goals.
Again, for the moment, they're all the same,
but we got no error here in the console,
no error in our code,
and also not in the terminal,
and we therefore now also know
how to useState with TypeScript
and how we can make sure that TypeScript understands
which type of value we wanna manage here.